VENKAT RAMSHESH

WORK HISTORY

Field Engineer, 05/2022 - present United States Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS)

- Installation and support for laptops, workstations, and AV equipment of USCIS staff, students, classroom, and offices
- Regular system software updates, hardware fixes, imaging of computers, maintenance of system servers and switches, remote worker support
- Certified in AWS Solutions Architect Associate and Certified Cloud Practitioner. Implemented VPC's, EC2 instances, fully elastic and scalable architectures, elastic beanstalk, SAM, S3 buckets and static website, pre signed URLs, NAT gateways, lambda and step functions, cloud formation templates, API gateways, VPN, file systems, transfer family, block and file storages, SAM, Cognito, CDN, Athena, and more. Studying for the AWS Professional certifications currently
- Learnt Python, HTML/CSS (front-end) and Flask (back-end) programming during personal time. Implemented projects including personal blog and website, API creation, pomodoro, rain alert, Spotify songs list, Stock tracker, password generator and more. Deployed python built API on Heroku. Used libraries like Flask, Requests, Pandas, Matplotlib, Plotly, NumPy, Selenium, Boto3, Beautiful soup and Turtle. (Code for some projects: https://github.com/kris1878/pythonprojects)

Field Engineer II, 11/2020 - 05/2021 Cytek Biosciences

- Installation and support for Aurora flow cytometer in Philly/NJ area in a timely manner
- Regular system preventative and update visits
- Identified major issues that could arise and provided solutions for these problems

Field Engineer II, 04/2020 - 11/2020 Cytiva

- Installation and support for OMX super resolution microscopes (OMX V3, V4, SR, SR plus and LEX models) in North America, Asia and Europe in a timely manner
- · Troubleshooting and fixing system issues on-site and remotely
- Minimizing average downtimes ~1 week
- Yearly preventive maintenance (PM) and hardware/software updates
- Adjusting parts stock, generating install and PM reports, quotations

Field Engineer I, 01/2015 - 03/2020 GE Healthcare Lifesciences

- Installation and support for GE OMX super resolution (OMX V3, V4, SR and SR plus models) and Delta Vision microscopes in North America, Asia and Europe
- Troubleshooting and fixing system issues on-site and remotely
- Yearly PM and hardware/software updates
- Customer support and training of end users both remotely and on site, updating manuals
- Hired and supervised subcontractors to improve production and meet critical deadlines.
- Interacted effectively with site engineering team and field staff to coordinate work that complied with design and installation documents

Research Instructor/Facility Manager, 07/2011 - 12/2014 Medical University of South Carolina

 Provide bioengineering and managerial support for the successful day to day working of the Advanced Imaging Core which include eight confocal,







PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Motivated, collaborative biomedical engineer skilled in IT, programming, and microscopy. Effective field engineer offering excellent skills in installation, training, maintenance and testing of systems. Forward-thinking professional offering years of experience working in fast-paced environments. Known for reliability and knowledge. Organized and dependable candidate successful at managing multiple priorities with a positive attitude. Willingness to take on added responsibilities to meet team goals

CERTIFICATIONS

 AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate, September 2022 CVBPEGQCRJE4Q1S0



• AWS cloud practitioner, June 2022 KCZ7CJ8JFEB4Q0KH



- Programming for Everybody (Getting Started with Python) XCZBAVAEH675
- Cisco Certified Network Associate, May 2000

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

Python, Matlab, C, Image J, HTML/CSS

EDUCATION

Ph.D, Biomedical Engineering, 2008 University of North Carolina - Chapel Hill

M.S, Biomedical Engineering, 2002 University of North Carolina - Chapel Hill

B.E, Instrumentation Engineering, 1999 Mumbai University/University of Mumbai - Mumbai

- multiphoton & fluorescence microscopes and image processing workstations
- Instruct users on microscopy/imaging usage and projects, consult on projects involving use of light microscopy techniques within and outside the university
- Organizer and instructor for the 2014 Fifth and 2012 Fourth Charleston Light Microscopy Workshop for the Biosciences
- Assisted in successful NIH grant application as part of Cell and Molecular Imaging resource
- Led facility management staff and consultants in producing business plan that focused on facility operations

Bioengineer/Facility Manager, 12/2007 - 06/2011 Medical University of South Carolina

- Provide bioengineering and managerial support for the successful day to day working of the center for cell death, injury and regeneration (CCDIR) and cell and molecular imaging resources
- Organized and instructed for the 2010 Third and 2008 Second Charleston Light Microscopy Workshop for the Biosciences
- Assisted in successful NCI and NIH grant application from Hollings Cancer Center as part of Cell and Molecular Imaging resource
- Evaluated facility operations and personnel for safety and health regulations compliance

PROFFESIONAL ACTIVITIES

- Reviewer for Journal of Biomedical Optics, Microscopy & Microanalysis and Methods
- Intravital Imaging Symposium at NIH, Bethesda, May 2011
- 2009 Workshop on FRET Microscopy, University of Virginia, Charlottesville
- Analytical and Quantitative Light Microscopy Course 2006, Marine Biological Laboratory, Woods Hole, Massachusetts

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Member of UNC squash team
- Recreational salsa dancer

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

Ramshesh VK and Lemasters JJ. Imaging of mitochondrial pH using SNARF.
Methods Mol Biol. 2012; 810:243-8

Ramshesh VK, Lemasters JJ. Pinhole shifting lifetime imaging microscopy (PSLIM). Journal of Biomedical Optics, 13 (6):064001, Nov-Dec 2008

Lemasters JJ, Ramshesh VK, Imaging of mitochondrial polarization and depolarization with cationic fluorophores. Mitochondria, Methods in Cell Biology 2007; L.A. Pon, E.A. Schon Eds.; 80: 283-295

Ramshesh VK, Knisley SB. Use of light absorbers to alter optical interrogation with epi-illumination and transillumination in 3-d cardiac models. Journal of Biomedical Optics 2006; 11

Ramshesh VK, Knisley SB. Spatial localization of cardiac optical mapping with multiphoton excitation. Journal of Biomedical Optics 2003; 8:253-259